We have a second uh 30inut keynote uh
before we jump into main tracks and that
that uh next keynote is going to be from
Sean Roberts from Netifi who's the VP of
applied AI. Um, now this is a this is a
really interesting session because I
think when we think about how we have
built software over time and we think
about our core kind of like ICP when we
when we build that software we think
about the user and the user being very
often a human a developer or or just a
consumer of our services but times have
changed with the adoption of agents
being you know so in our face with
everything AI it's important that when
we when we think about you know
providing these services prov providing
these these tools, we think about agents
as users of that as well as developers.
And so this session is really going to
kind of like compare the two and talk
about how we can plan with agents in
mind as our users. So, uh, please
welcome on stage Sean Roberts.
[applause]
[music]
Thanks.
All right. Hello everyone. Um, as Simon
said, I'm Sean Roberts. I lead the AI
programs at Netlefi. [snorts] Um, and
I've been working trying to make the web
better, more secure, faster for a very
long time. And especially at Netifi,
I've been really trying to figure out
how we can provide the best agent
experience that we can for our platform,
but also trying to figure out how the
web and agents can work really well
together.
And so with that, you know, let's dive
into the talk today around agent
experience. And I don't know the makeup
of the crowd, but if you don't know what
this is referencing, that's not a me
problem. Um, you know, take a picture,
share with your friendly neighborhood AI
agent, and they will tell you it's
definitely in the training data. Um, but
really what we're talking about today is
how how agent experience is an extension
of developer experience. Um, a quick
raise of hands or or horns here. Um, who
is a senior plus dev or in charge of a
codebase today? A bunch of you. Yeah.
Horns. Yes. Uh, all right. Raise your
hands again if you feel like you are a
steward of the developer experience of
your codebase today.
Yes. Yes. All right. Well, thank you for
your service. Uh, this is often a very
thankless task. Um, but it's incredibly
important because, um, as we know, you
know, developer experience really is the
sum. uh it's greater than the sum of all
of its parts, right? To have a great
developer experience, you really need to
have good documentation, onboarding,
there's intuitive design that goes into
it, it's an intentional act that you put
into it. Like, but the reality is is if
you're allowing people to develop on
your platform or on your codebase, you
have a developer experience. That does
not mean it's good. It just means you
have one. Just like every software has a
user experience if they have users.
And with agent experience, it's very
similar, right? Um we have hit this
critical mass where it it's not a
question of whether or not agents are
working on your codebase or or on your
platform. They are. The question is
whether or not you're supporting those.
And when we talk about agent experience,
we do mean that kind of holistic
experience that an agent has interacting
with your system or your codebase.
And to illustrate this right um again
you know when we think about developer
experience we think about these
developers over here who are
handcrafting
beautiful error-free artisal code. It's
great. Um and and the the quality of
them going from here to here is really
determined by the quality of the
developer experience. And now we have
developers who are delegating work to
agents um to do parts of this on their
behalf. And when we talk about agent
experience, we're talking about this
connection here. So the how well are
they able to achieve you the same amount
of of work. Um, and and this connection
is all predicated on how well the agent
experience is.
And I think it's very important to
emphasize we're talking a lot about the
agents experience here, but this is all
to benefit the human developer on the
other side of it. This is nothing to do
with replacing developers. There are
developers delegating work to an agent.
And the more successful we can make
them, the more successful we can make
them, right? That's the whole point of
this. It's also worth noting that when
we talk about agent experience, we're
talking about it today in in regards to
a codebase, but an agent experience is
this discipline that spans much broader,
right? Um going forward, e-commerce is
going to have to figure out how they
serve their customers who are using
agents to buy on their behalf. um
flights, how how they you know book
flights and and airline tickets when an
agent was used to delegate. Um so it's
not specific to us but it's very
important as right now agents are best
at working with our code bases. Um but
as Guy described they are have a lot of
room for improvement. So one more time
who who's in charge of the developer
experience of their codebase here
yet? Oh, a lot left's hands. A lot of
people decided not to. But now, everyone
of you holding your uh your hands up and
probably everyone in this room really,
you're also in charge of the agent
experience. It doesn't like maybe that
used to be a question mark before. It's
not anymore. Like it is a part of
serving developers is acknowledging the
fact that developers are using agents to
also work with your codebase. Um
[snorts]
so you have this charge now. It's very
straightforward but um there there's
you know having an agent experience and
using agents isn't a new thing but where
we are today is this thing I call this
mini oneperson band problem like we've
all you know have gone off our teams
individually have gone off figured out
what works for them and they've kind of
culminated like kind of like their view
of the world and like they have their
whole setup right um and then two days
ago Gemini 3 came out and someone with
10 years experience using anti-gravity
IDE said you should stop what you're
doing here and then switch to this and
so someone will and then now your team
kind of you know expands its surface
area and so forth and then you know
there's probably there's going to be
another tool next week and the next you
know a few weeks and and we get this
kind of sprawl we we have individually
went out figured things out and and
we've built this this is the kind of
mini oneperson band problem that we see
with with developer uh AI native tooling
today.
How many of you have gone to a band
where there's like four or five of these
playing at the same time? Or go gone to
a concert, there's four or five. Yeah,
zero of you cuz they can't. And but you
know, because these are this is not a
band. These are three individuals maybe
trying to do their own thing. Maybe
towards the same end, but this not a
band. Okay. Um
this is a band. So a again ask your AI.
Um this is a band. they they have
purpose-built um you know tools. They
are all trying to come together for the
same goal to to make um great
experiences for for their customers,
their audience, right? And that's really
important because together they're able
to do far more than any one person band,
right? Um and you know, for those who
like the orchestra metaphor better,
there you go. Um,
all right. So, now what what is it that
we actually need to do in order to to
have a better agent experience? Um, to
to improve the developer experience of
our code bases.
Um, and thankfully Guy did a lot of the
examples and homework for me earlier.
So, that's awesome. Uh, but I'll dive
into the the other parts of it. I I
think what's really important for us to
to make sure that it's clear on is
there's no specific solution. I wish we
could say this if you do this you're
done, you know, pack it up, let's go
home. Uh but there's not agent
experience is a discipline, not a
specific tool. Okay? And just so so if
you're if you're thinking about, okay, I
have to support agents, so I just need
an MCP server. That's all I need. Check
the box. Done. that's thinking far too
narrowly about this problem. And whether
it's MCP, ADA, ACP,
these are all solutions that are kind of
under under the umbrella of an agent
experience. Um, but the other reality is
we're all still figuring it out. We have
a lot of ideas about what works today
and then we're going to prove those
wrong tomorrow and then we're going to
keep iterating on it. But we're right in
the middle of it. And so where should
you actually start? So this is going to
be my recommendation around the kind of
crawl, walk, run stages that you can
take on to to start either start your
journey or expand it going forward.
So the first thing like if if your team
is just a bunch of one person bands um
or not doing any of this at all, start
with figuring that out, right? Like I
think that there's a hunch, yeah, my
team's using AI, whatever. Like like we
we're AI native. It's like, no, like
like figure out what they're using. Ask
them, figure out what's working, what's
not. And and this doesn't have to be a
big effort. Get a Google form, whatever,
vibe code it, and just ask them what
what agents are they using? What's
working well? And to be clear, don't ask
them the question that we asked them a
year ago, two years ago. We're like,
"Have you tried any agents?" It's like,
no. Like, everyone's probably tried an
AI tool, but what we want to know is
what people are using every day or every
other day. What's working? it's not.
And it's important to understand that
for for many reasons, but not least of
which is the fact that there are lots of
AI agents and tools and combinations of
them. And then all the work that you're
going to be doing to um improve the
agent experience. This helps scope it
much better. Just understand what people
are doing. If they're using spec driven
development, that might be a little
different looking of an agent experience
than if they're using some some other
tool or they're really into stuff like
lovable or bolt things like that.
So audit audit what people are doing.
Figure out what's going on. Um and then
start to build your internal community,
right? all that really, you know, has to
all that is really involved in doing
that is getting them together every, you
know, infrequently, but get them
together to talk about the issues that
they're running into. Talk about the
tools that they're using. Um, if you
really want to learn something cool,
come up with a problem or take something
some take some ticket off the board and
say, "Hey, I'm going to solve this
together and I'm going to watch you
solve it your way. I'm going to solve it
my way and we're going to we're going to
learn together." And that's some version
of of pair programming here. Uh where
there's also an AI agent involved and
that is so illuminating in terms of like
how what people understand differently
about the different the code base how
they approach the problem and and it
will also start to build up your
internal community um to to build
towards an agent experience.
So taking the next step forward, right?
Uh you know the agents that you need to
support
now you need to help them be better. Guy
did an a fantastic job of explaining
this for me earlier with with with some
data around backing up that uh the LLMs
themselves are not sufficient in terms
of understanding your codebase. Um
[snorts] and and the reality is is if
there is a gap in knowledge, it will
confidently make things up or decide for
you. It's not always made up false. It
just might just be totally different.
Like his example of picking a theme that
was not the right theme
um to combat this, right? Context files
are where you need to spend your initial
time, right? Um either you know
depending on the tools, right? agents
files, steering files, cloud code uh
cloud files, cloudmd files. um these are
going to be very important um nuggets of
information and you know some rules of
thumb that I think about is if uh
if you could if you couldn't simplify
something make it obvious right so many
code bases you see like okay to run a
test suite it's this some magical
command that you got to run that's not
obvious if if you have those make sure
that they're in your context um
other areas are like if you have a
decoupled architecture so you have a
front
um that's decoupled from your backend
which might be decoupled from your your
data layer etc. It doesn't necessarily
know those connections and you need to
make those clear or it will make those
connections it it'll make them up every
time. [snorts] Um and that's going to be
incredibly important. Um and and and
especially whenever you get into this
world of as people are
um iterating on this and they start
finding that
hey it's it something that we thought
was obvious wasn't it's going to keep
making those things up and adding those
into your um uh agents files and and
steering files is going to be incredibly
important. [snorts] The next thing I
mentioned um is is the core dependency
uh documentation. I'd mentioned the core
dependency of the the front end has a
dependency on this back end. It's over
here. Here's how you use it. Here's how
you find information about it. And
that's incredibly important, but there's
also this this problem of um dependency
uh documentation and like third party
modules, things like that, even first
party separated modules. And and and Guy
went in uh a lot of detail about that.
This has been bothering me for so long.
Um because you know the reality is
especially with you know brownfield type
of projects is
I I have developers or so the model is
trained on version one of my API the
latest version is version three but all
my developers are using version two and
so like it messes it up nine times out
of 10 um and and the the tooling for
getting this right isn't great today. I
was actually, you know, writing this, I
was very stoked to see Tesla's, you
know, registry and things like that that
they're doing. Um, and so I'm gonna
explore that more. I think that's very
exciting. And I definitely agree that
there's actually, um, more onus needs to
be put on the open source community to
deliver these things. The way I kind of
see the Tesla registry is like, well, if
every uh, dependency had to have its
types hosted somewhere else, right? like
really the types the documentation for
it really needs to be there. But we also
have the second problem where especially
open source repos
there's people who build on them and
then there's people who use them and
those are different documentation and so
like even it still gets a little bit
harder and harder the the more you try
to optimize but again we're all figuring
this out together so that's fine. Um if
if you use context 7 that's also
something that uh people people use. Uh,
I've I've run into issues with it not
doing very well on the versioning side
of things. Um, but regardless, if you
have a key dependency that's a third
party module,
make sure it's in your context. Make
sure you're using it right, especially
if it's things like data based
databased um uh because there's it's
just a such a dense topic and tool set
that um it ends up getting pretty
confused with those types of tools. So
make it clear and especially for very
large code bases. Um the concept of
knowledge graphs um there's many
different implementations of them.
Cognition released uh deep wiki and and
code maps recently.
But it's this you know the reality is is
if you have a really large codebase and
you're asking it to do things every time
that you try to ask it to do something
it's got to kind of figure it out on its
own. And the larger the code base, the
longer that takes, the more expensive it
is, the more likely it is it's going to
miss parts or get confused.
And this is where knowledge graphs
really come in where you can kind of
pre-roduce
this kind of understanding of the
overall architecture, how things relate
to one another, and summarize those. And
so before it tries to do things, it
consults there first. And those are very
helpful for larger code bases. [snorts]
Uh feedback loops are going to be
incredibly important. Um, so if you're
if you're already getting your internal
community together, working with them to
say, "Look, whenever we're having an
issue, if if a human had to manually
intervene in an agent uh agent's
workflow, get that documented. Get that
into context." Um, if you're talking to
that senior engineer who's been there
for 15 years and has all the tribal
knowledge in their head, if you every
time you have to consult them, if that
doesn't go back in documentation or
context, I don't know what you're doing.
But like that that's this internal
feedback loop. You have to have some
forcing functions to make sure that your
agents understand because unlike you,
they they can't go ask uh necessarily
that that uh that tenure developer who
has all the information in their head.
So establish feedback loops with your
internal team.
One practice that I really enjoy doing
is I have this MC MCP where it's like,
okay, if the agent's really going off
the rails here, um, I have it look back
and say, what could we have done better
here? It's like an agent therapy
session. Like, what what should we do
better to make sure that you're going to
get this right next time? And
specifically update the context files to
make sure that happens. And then
especially like once we do that um
assuming it makes sense at the time
having it try again and then go from
there. Uh I have a lot of good results
with that as well.
I'm sure most of you if not all of you
are using AI review tools in in your um
uh code bases and your CI pipelines and
such. the so I won't go too deep into
that but like the one thing that I think
is an addition on top of that is not
only having your your uh AI review tool
figure out what's wrong with a thing but
also suggests when there are patterns
that were missing from your context
files that would have prevented this
from happening in the future. So like
this is you're getting towards a step of
trying to automate some of this feedback
loop.
Ephemeral environments are something I'm
a huge fan of. Um, you know, at Netlifi,
we can we we do deployments for like
pre-product deployments or preview
deployments. Um, and we can do as many
of them as as the agent needs or as the
developer needs and they're amazing
feedback tools for everything that's not
specifically code related, right? Right?
So, if it's like the style of a thing or
the layout of a thing, if it's just
making stuff up, you can both have the
the human review these things as or as
well as, you know, if you want to give
access to the the agent to review these
things on your behalf. These really and
then combining these things. So, an
agent figures out, okay, I messed up the
layout here. I'm going to go fix it. I'm
also going to make sure I document this
in the context. Now, you're really
starting to see a this full end to end
picture. And this is ultimately what you
kind of end up with with with a good
agent experience and feedback uh life
cycle. So developer can delegate works
to to to the agents. They generate the
code and this again this being the the
agent experience that they have access
to here. They are better at doing this
because the feedback loop of making sure
the context is good um uh appropriate um
for for the jobs that they're doing and
so on. they can, you know, you have your
your reviewer agents figuring out, hey,
this should have been done differently.
I'm going to make sure that they know
that going forward. Um, I can also make
sure that they can review the the actual
changes, not just the code, but also the
the output of that code and and then
make suggestions for doing better going
forward.
Okay. And as we get into the um,
you know, you're really advancing your
your your the aging experience of your
codebase. Um shared sub aents is a
really cool unlock. So shared uh sub
aents these are going to be like guy
mentioned earlier um these are as simple
as just markdown files of defining hey
this is a specialized agent because by
default all these agents are generalists
right and as we know full stack
developers they can get the job done but
a specialist is probably going to get it
done at least a little bit better if not
completely better. um these are your
specialized sub aents. You define them
in a markdown file and then so you can
say okay this is our methodology for
design this is our meth methodology for
copyrightiting it has our voice and tone
in it this is our data migrations sub
agent this is they are specialized at
doing this and what's going to be really
um
the the big difference that you're going
to see here is that when you ask it to
do something you have sub agents it's
going to say oh actually it's better for
this one to go do it and it will kick
that one off and it has specialized
context. Now, imagine you had five
specializations that you wanted to
really hone in on and tune and you had
to throw all that context into a single
cloud MD file or agents MD file. That
does not work well. And that's kind of
why we have these now. We figured out
that that doesn't work well. You
overload the context. It gets confused.
It starts to steal attention and and
things like that. So this is uh shared
so agents are are very important and and
and really allow you to have a shared
way of doing things across your code
bases and across um your different
developers.
You have your context files, you have
your uh steering files, and now you have
uh sub aents files. You're immediately
going to run into how do I distribute
these things? Um because as soon as you
have more than one repo as guy was
mentioning these things are are you know
there there are things that are repo
specific that always should be in the
repo and then there's going to be things
that are global. Your voice and tone for
your brand that's a global thing. Um
your brand style guides all that stuff
global. How you might you know do
reviews all those things are global. Um,
but how do you share that across your
your developer base, which might be, you
know, dozens or, you know, potentially
thousands of people. Um,
and my my preferred methodology
personally is to centralize these things
into uh the globals into a shared repo
and then having a CLI that people can
run to update them and do that those
things. And um I also learned through
guys talk that they they have this
capability on the Tesla um platform as
well. But I think that once you like
this is a good problem to have. Okay,
we've defined rules. They're working
really well in our code bases. We
actually need to propagate this so that
we're working better across multiple
code bases. Um, and centralizing these
outside of a single agent as guy also
mentioned is incredibly important
because like if it doesn't like like you
did this audit step one unless they all
said I only use cloud code and they only
all they all only use codecs then
picking one agent is a recipe for
disaster. Also, if they're all only
using one agent, you you're probably
already setting yourself up for for a
future problem. Um but uh yeah so so
centralize these um if you don't use a
platform like Tesla you can use
centralized GitHub repo that also has a
CLI to run to to do the syncs
and I think really on the bleeding edge
of of these uh optimizing your agent
experience um [snorts] we we we had
these opportunities to run evals on the
AX of our of our code bases and if you
haven't used or done The um agent evals
all they really are are putting an agent
under certain conditions asking to do
certain task and evaluating the
performance of it doing those things.
But have you ever considered taking now
cloud SDK or codeex SDK throwing that in
eval saying hey
try to do some stuff on my on my repo
and then help me figure out what I
should tell you to do that better.
You're doing these things wrong. um you
know guy and the Tesla team have done a
lot of this on the open source side of
things but this um doing this for your
own repo is incredibly uh important
incredibly validating.
It will really help you close the gaps
between what's just clear in your
documentation today and what's still
missing.
In addition to helping you fill gaps, it
also helps you solve the the the one-way
ratchet problem or it's a asmov's law of
bureaucracy. I totally knew that before
yesterday.
[laughter]
Um which which says right like um laws
and regulations once they're enacted
monotonically just grow. They never
contract. They and they never
substantially get repealed or or
reduced. And we are seeing that
happening with config or with with
context rules and context as well.
They're just growing. We're like, "Ah, I
missed this thing. I'm going to keep
adding to it." So, but how do you safely
feel confident in peeling back some of
those requirements? And how do you do
how do you um you know, you fix this
issue, but you cause other issues. How
do you feel confident about not doing
that? And I think eval for for the agent
experience is going to be incredibly
important.
Um cool. So we covered a lot of ground
in terms of you know the developer
experience. We we all understand that's
our charge now. We're we're we've been
in charge of the developer experience
for our code bases but agent experience
is no longer optional. That's a part of
what we have to deal with now. Um not
because we want to support agents but
because we want to support our
developers who use agents. Okay.
and making this I was really um
stoked on on using the band a whole
metaphor because I think what's really
important about bands is the size of
them doesn't uh determine the success of
them, right? It doesn't matter how big
your band is, but what does matter is
how well they can perform together and
and produce uh great outcomes. And so
when we think about all the things that
we've heard with like, oh, if you use
these tools, you'll be a 10x developer.
So now we get one one person band and
this other 10x developer wants to be
their own oneperson band. But what's
really magical is is having um
a 10x team, right? And and that really
comes when when we're all sharing
knowledge and we're all working
together. Um, as as the the as Bon Scott
said from AC/DC, um, it's a long way to
the top if you want to rock and roll,
but I would amend that to say it's a
much more enjoyable ride if you're with
your friends and with your band and
you're going together. So, with that,
thank you all. Thank you for coming
here. Drink some water. Go make good
space. [applause]
[music]
Heat. Heat.